<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tags: Programming | Erik Bergenholtz' blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/categories/programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/"/>
  <updated>2018-02-03T23:25:01+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erik Bergenholtz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Classy With Haskell]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/12/18/getting-classy-with-haskell/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-18T23:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/12/18/getting-classy-with-haskell</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought that the next post I was going to do would be one on higher order
functions. In fact, I started writing one a couple of times, but it just didn&rsquo;t
seem necessary. Why was that? Well, it all actually made sense. I had a read
through the chapter, and the theory wan&rsquo;t that hard. Once I had also
reimplemented the fold and scan functions recusively myself I felt that I had
a quite solid grip on higher order functions. And man, are they powerful!</p>

<p>Now I&rsquo;ve moved forward, past modules and into the end of defining my own
data types. While that is itself quite straight forward, there are quite
a few things that aren&rsquo;t exactly odd, but they need to be remebered, so I&rsquo;m
jotting it down here.</p>

<p>To star off, if you want to define a new data type you use the <code>data</code> keyword.
It looks like this:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">data TrafficLight = Red | Yellow | Green
</code></pre>

<p>This will create a data type called <code>TrafficLight</code>, of which we can create the
values <code>Red</code>, <code>Yellow</code> and <code>Green</code> using it&rsquo;s <em>value constructors</em>. While this
is a perfectly fine class, we can&rsquo;t print it to the terminal, read it from a
string, order it or check if it&rsquo;s values are equal at present. To fix that we
could do the following:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">data TrafficLight = Red | Yellow | Green deriving (Show, Read, Eq, Ord)
</code></pre>

<p>This allow us to do everything stated above. The <code>Eq</code> type class (we&rsquo;ll get to
that later) allow us to equate elements. The default behaviour is that
<code>Red == Red</code> is true, while <code>Red == Green</code> is false. The <code>Ord</code> allow us to
order the values. The default behaviour for this type class is that the value
constructors <em>to the left</em> are <strong>smaller</strong> than the ones on the right. I.e., in
this example <code>Red &lt; Green</code> is true while <code>Yellow &gt; Green</code> is false, because of
the order they&rsquo;re defined in the type definition.</p>

<p>It is also possible to define a new data type using a class constructor. This
is something that&rsquo;s been used in the type definitions of functions through out
the book, and isn&rsquo;t that strange really. For instance, a simple binary search
tree could be implemented like this:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">data Tree a = EmptyTree | Node a (Tree a) (Tree a) deriving (Ord, Eq, Show)
</code></pre>

<p>Using this kind of declaration, it is possible to store any data type in the
tree, as long as it is orderable and equatable. Which makes sense, since it&rsquo;s a
BST.</p>

<p>We can also use the register syntax to add some additional context to our data
type:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">data Person = { firstname :: String
              , lastname  :: String
              , birthyear :: Int
              }
</code></pre>

<p>All this is quite straight forward, if a bit much to take in all at once. But
it quite makes sense anyway. Now, let&rsquo;s get into the really strange things.
Let&rsquo;s start off with instances.</p>

<p>Earlier I showed that in order to make the value constructors of a class
equatable (is that even a word? Sounds weird) you need to derive the <code>Eq</code> type
class in your data type. This imposes some default behaviour, as described. If
you for some reason aren&rsquo;t happy with this default behaviour you can go around
it by making your type an <em>instance</em> of <code>Eq</code>, like this (I&rsquo;m using the
TrafficLight type for this example):</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">instance Eq TrafficLight where
    Red == Red = True
    Yellow == Yellow = True
    Green == Green = True
    _ == _ = False
</code></pre>

<p>This basically says that <code>Red == Red</code> is true, and so is <code>Yellow == Yellow</code> and
<code>Green == Green</code>. All other combinations, however, are false. This overrides
how <code>Eq</code> typically behaves (and in this case, replaces the behaviour with an
identical behaviour). I can really see how this is useful, as it bares some
resemblance to defining your own equality operator (or the like; this works for
any type class) in C++.</p>

<p>Next up is actual type classes, and inheritance from those. Coming from a (sort
of) object oriented (I bloody hate object oriented programming..) background,
this seems quite strange. A class in Haskell isn&rsquo;t like a class in C++; a bunch
of functions and variables crammed together into one name. In Haskel, it&rsquo;s just
a collection of type definitions for functions. In other words, it&rsquo;s kind of
like a C++ class with no variables and only virtual functions. If you have a
class that itself is a type constructor, then you can make the class a subclass
of another class. For instance, the <code>Ord</code> class is a subclass of <code>Eq</code>,
because it makes sense that any data types that are orderable are also
equatable.</p>

<p>As a grand finale of this monstrosity of a post, we have functors. Oh dear, how
weird functors seemed at first. A type class that is meant for things that can
be mapped. It sounded so strange at first, but once I realized how it could
be utilized for any data type that can either be empty, or contain something,
it was quite obvious how awesome this was. For instance, the <code>Tree</code> I
defined earlier has the following definition:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">data Tree a = EmptyTree | Node a (Tree a) (Tree a) derives (Show)
</code></pre>

<p>Now, say I want to write a function that traverses all of the tree and applies
an arbitrary function to the values of each node. Using functors it&rsquo;s as easy
as:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">instance Functor Tree where
    fmap _ EmptyTree = EmptyTree
    fmap f (Node a b c) = Node (f a) (fmap f b) (fmap f c)
</code></pre>

<p>That&rsquo;s it! I tell Haskell that I want to make the Tree type an instance of the
Functor class, I define how I want the <code>fmap</code> function to act on the tree and
as a result I can now multiply all node values of a tree of integers like this:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">fmap (*2) tree
</code></pre>

<p>It goes over the tree and builds a new tree. Writing this I realize that doing
this with a normal function would actually work the exact same way, but I am
sure that functors have some advantage over normal functions that I just don&rsquo;t
see with my inexperienced eyes.</p>

<p>So, after a long read (both for me and you) we&rsquo;re finally at the end of this
post (and the chapters on types and classes in &ldquo;Learn you a Haskell&rdquo;). It&rsquo;s
been quite the journey, and it has taken me a couple of days to get here, which
makes sense considering I&rsquo;ve had to forget everything I know about classes. But
Haskell&rsquo;s type system seems really cool, and I look forward to getting to know
it better! But now I&rsquo;ll take a break. Until next time,</p>

<p>Happy Hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Made a Home Screen]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/12/13/i-made-a-home-screen/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-13T23:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/12/13/i-made-a-home-screen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve just finished a small project that I wanted to share with the rest of you.
What I&rsquo;ve done is a home screen for your browser that at least I think is
pretty good looking (see screenshot below) and faily easy to customize. The
page uses a number of simple JavaScripts (that could probably be improved) to
print a nifty, randomized title on the page, as well as dynamically build links
to the sites you frequent.</p>

<p>If you think this looks nice and want to try it out, all instructions you
should need to get it up and running to your liking is on the
<a href="https://github.com/Psyberion/homepage">repo on github</a>, so I&rsquo;m not going to
say more about it, but leave you with a screenshot.</p>

<p>Happy hacking!</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/Psyberion/homepage"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/fP3xg5H.png" alt="Screenshot of homepage" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Like Recursive]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/12/11/i-like-recursive/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-11T23:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/12/11/i-like-recursive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here we are again, another post about Haskell. To star off I just want to say
that I am having a blast learning this, and that I think I am getting the
hang of it. I&rsquo;ve gone through recursion today, which isn&rsquo;t really a new concept
to me, but it&rsquo;s tricky to know what to do in a completely new language.
However, I managed to write all example function from the book on my own, which
I think is a sign that I am starting to get this. For instance, I came up with
this solution to writing quicksort:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">quicksort :: (Ord a) =&gt; [a] -&gt; [a]
quicksort [] = []
quicksort [x] = [x]
quicksort (x:xs) = quicksort lower ++ [x] ++ quicksort higher
    where lower  = [y | y &lt;- xs, y&lt;=x]
          higher = [z | z &lt;- xs, z &gt;x]
</code></pre>

<p>The definition in the book was:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">quicksort :: (Ord a) =&gt; [a] -&gt; [a]
quicksort [] = []
quicksort (x:xs) =
    let smallerOrEqual = [a | a &lt;- xs, a &lt;= x]
        larger = [a | a &lt;- xs, a &gt; x]
    in quicksort smallerOrEqual ++ [x] ++ quicksort larger
</code></pre>

<p>So the only real differences is that I have one unnecessary case in my pattern
matching (<code>quicksort [x] = [x]</code>) and that I use <code>where</code> instead of <code>let</code>. I&rsquo;m
quite satisfied with that!</p>

<p>The next chapter is on currying, folds and other strange things. From what I
remember, these things all appeared very odd to me, so I think I&rsquo;ll take that
tomorrow instead. So I guess I didn&rsquo;t really learn that much today, but it&rsquo;s
nice to see that I am getting closer to understanding this language.</p>

<p>Anyway, expect a monster update when I&rsquo;m done with the next chapter, because
there&rsquo;ll be a lot to anchor in my mind by writing about it. Until then,</p>

<p>Happy Hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Haskell Peculiarities]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/12/10/more-haskell-peculiarities/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-10T23:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/12/10/more-haskell-peculiarities</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My mission to learn Haskell goes on, and I&rsquo;ve now  read about functions. As
Haskell is a purley functional language, it makes sense that functions are
quite important and well developed in the language. There are a lot of things
I really like with the way Haskell does functions that are strange in the eyes
of an imperative programmer, and I&rsquo;m going to jot some of it down here to try
to reinforce my own understanding of it.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s start with <em>guards</em>. In Haskell, a guard is basically a large if-else
statement. The syntax is as follows:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">function var
    | var == 1 = statement
    | var == 2 = statement
</code></pre>

<p>For instance, if I want to build a function that returns <code>True</code> if the input is
even I could write it like this</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">even:: (Integral a) =&gt; a -&gt; Bool
even x
   | x `mod` 2 == 0 = True
   | x `mod` 2 == 1 = False
</code></pre>

<p>This makes for code that is quite easy to read, especially when there are a lot
of different cases to match against. Speaking of cases, there are of course
switch-case statements in Haskell too, but just like if-statements they aren&rsquo;t
statements but expressions. That means that the following is valid in Haskell:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">length' xs = "The list is " ++ case xs of []    -&gt; "empty
                                          [x]   -&gt; "a singleton"
                                          (x:_) -&gt; "a long list"
</code></pre>

<p>Another thing that I really like is the <code>where</code> binding. It allows you to bind
an expression to a name in the scope of a function. That means that the <code>even</code>
function from earlier could be rewritten like this:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">even:: (Integral a) =&gt; a -&gt; bool
even x
     | m == 0 = True
     | m == 1 = False
     where m = x `mod` 2
</code></pre>

<p>Finally, there&rsquo;s the <code>let</code> expression. In my opinion (this may well change as I
get to know the language better) it seems to be most usable in list
comprehensions, like this:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">[double | x&lt;-[1..100] , let double=x*2]
</code></pre>

<p>Anyway, that&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;ve learnt today. Writing this I got some of the syntax
wrong, but that&rsquo;s to expect when I&rsquo;ve just started out. I think I grasp the
concepts though, so that&rsquo;s really nice. Next up is recursion, which should be
a blast. But now I&rsquo;m going to sleep.</p>

<p>Happy hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Me a Haskell for Great Good]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/12/09/learning-me-a-haskell-for-great-good/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-09T23:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/12/09/learning-me-a-haskell-for-great-good</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I was informed roughly what I will be doing at work next semester (when I
say &ldquo;roughly&rdquo; I mean that the suggested work load probably is way through the
roof, and that it will need to be adjusted before the term starts), and one
of the things I&rsquo;ll be spending my time on is research. Since I am just a
project assistant and not a PhD student my research will be quite limited by
time (I will only spend 80 hours on it over the entire semester), but it&rsquo;s
something.</p>

<p>What my supervisor want me to do is have a look at a parsing library for
Haskell called <a href="https://github.com/aslatter/parsec">Parsec</a>. There&rsquo;s only one
problem; I don&rsquo;t know Haskell. Yet. So, today I set out on my journey to learn
my first functional programming language, and I thought I&rsquo;d let you in on the
fun. Starting with this post, I will be posting about my progress with learning
the (to me) new language. Maybe you&rsquo;ll be getting something out of it, maybe
not. I&rsquo;m going to do it regardless.</p>

<p>So, to start off I want to mention the book I&rsquo;ll be learning from. It&rsquo;s called
<a href="https://www.nostarch.com/lyah.htm">Learn You a Haskell for Great Good</a>, and is
published by <a href="https://www.nostarch.com/">No Starch Press</a>. I&rsquo;ll write a review
of the book once I&rsquo;m done working though it.</p>

<p>Now, without further adue, let&rsquo;s delve into Haskell! (Note that I&rsquo;m mostly by
no means going to try to teach you Haskell, I&rsquo;m mostly just going to ramble on
about things I find weird about the language)</p>

<p>As a C and Python programmer, Haskell seems quite strange. It feel a lot like
Python in the way that it is written, but some things are strange. For
instance, the following is perfectly legitimate syntax for Haskell:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">foo x = (if x&gt;100 then x else x*2)+1
</code></pre>

<p>First of all, this is a function declaration and not a variable assingment. But
that&rsquo;s not the main thing that&rsquo;s bugging me about this. It&rsquo;s that the <code>if</code>
itself <em>returns</em> a value, which I can then add <code>1</code> to. As the book expresses
it: there is no such thing as an <code>if</code> <em>statement</em> in Haksell, there are <code>if</code>
<em>expressions</em> instead. Very strange.</p>

<p>Another thing that is qutie odd, but does make sense, is the way list items are
accessed. Coming from imperative languages, I am used to the <code>list[index]</code>
syntax if I want to access a list element. However, that kind of syntax
wouldn&rsquo;t be possible in Haskell, since Haskell has no variables. Insted the
syntax is</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">[1, 2, 3, 4, 5] !! 3
</code></pre>

<p>This would fetch <code>4</code>, which is the third item of the list. To finish off, I
want to mention a thing that&rsquo;s really weird with Haskell, but it&rsquo;s something
I wish all languages did: argument pattern matching. For instance, to build a
(probably poor) summing function one could do the following:</p>

<pre><code class="haskell">sum' (x:xs) = x + sum' xs
sum' [] = 0
</code></pre>

<p>This basically means that the function <code>sum'</code> takes a list, and puts the first
element in it&rsquo;s own variable. It then adds that to the recursive call to the
function itself. Once the list is empty (the <code>sum' []</code>), <code>0</code> is returned. No
<code>if</code> expressions, nothing. Just matching the input with an empty list.
Bloody brilliant!</p>

<p>Anyway, this post is already way longer than it should, so I&rsquo;m going to sign
off now.</p>

<p>Happy hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
