<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tags: Reviews | Erik Bergenholtz' blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/categories/reviews/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/"/>
  <updated>2017-07-30T17:27:00+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erik Bergenholtz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: The Linux Commandline by William E. Shotts, Jr.]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/08/15/linux-commandline-review/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/08/15/linux-commandline-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s finally time for me to post my first book review! As mentioned I&rsquo;ve wanted
to do this for quite some time, both to get some more posting here on the blog
done and to give me an incentive to actually read the books I buy. So here it
is, the first book review on this blog!</p>

<p>The book I&rsquo;ve (actually) read is
<a href="https://www.nostarch.com/tlcl"><em>The Linux Commandline</em></a> by <strong>William E. Shotts,
Jr.</strong>, published by <a href="https://www.nostarch.com/">No Starch Press</a>. The book is
aimed at people who have just installed Linux and is clueless about where to go
from there. As such I am quite a bit outside of the target audience, but despite
this I found the book to be a very good read (I mean, I finished it&hellip;).</p>

<p><em>The Linux Commandline</em> is divided into four parts: Learning the shell;
Configuration and the Environment; Common Tasks and Essential Tools; and Writing
Shell Scripts. Just looking at this it is clear that the book covers a great
many subjects in the world of the Linux commandline. As I said it is aimed at
complete Linux newbies, and as such it begins at a very basic level. In the very
first chapter the concept of a <em>shell</em> is explained, along with things such as
the fact that the shell tells you that no command was found if you try to
execute random letters. Once that is dealt with the book works it&rsquo;s way from
commands like <code>cd</code> and <code>ls</code> to more complex commands like <code>sed</code> and how to write
regular expressions for <code>sed</code>. It covers pipes, redirection, searching with
<code>find</code> and touches on editing with my personal favorite editor Vim. When all
these topics are covered, the author shows how to glue it all together using
<code>if</code>-statements, <code>for</code>-loops and shell functions to build complete shell
scripts.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s obvious that the book covers a lot, but the big question is whether or not
it does it well. To that my answer is yes. As mentioned I am far from the target
audience with 10 years of working with Linux in my luggage. Despite this I
actually learned a thing or two from the book. A large part of the book could be
skimmed, such as descriptions of what <code>ls -l</code> and <code>ls -a</code> do, but some chapters
were completely new such as how to print files to paper via the CLI. Apart from
the content being very fleshed out it is also well written in a style that is
easy to read and learn from. Descriptions are clear and the vast majority of all
commands covered are also used in an example, so that it is easy for the reader
to follow along and try things out.</p>

<p>To conclude this is a book that according to me is clearly worth the $39.95. I
only own it as an e-book, but I am tempted to buy a paperback as well to have a
physical copy. It is well written, clearly describes how to efficiently work
with the shell on a basic to intermediate level, and I think that if everyone
who tried Linux would take the time to work through this their Linux experience
would be a lot better.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
