<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tags: General | Erik Bergenholtz' blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://erikbergenholtz.github.io/erikbergenholtz/blog/categories/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://erikbergenholtz.github.io/erikbergenholtz/"/>
  <updated>2017-07-30T14:32:45+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://erikbergenholtz.github.io/erikbergenholtz/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erik Bergenholtz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World 2.0]]></title>
    <link href="http://erikbergenholtz.github.io/erikbergenholtz/blog/2016/08/10/hello_world_2.0/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://erikbergenholtz.github.io/erikbergenholtz/blog/2016/08/10/hello_world_2.0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There we are. I have finally gotten around to rebuilding my blog. I&rsquo;ve been
mearning to do that for a couple of months, but there&rsquo;s been a lot going on
lately so I haven&rsquo;t had the time. Until now. I must say that I&rsquo;m quite
satisfied how it turned out. There are still a couple of things I want to
add to it, like a commenting feature, but I&rsquo;ll get to that Later<TM>.</p>

<p>Now, I know I&rsquo;ve been worse at posting here than a cat is at barking, but
I&rsquo;m hoping to change that because I&rsquo;ve got a lot going on! First things first,
I&rsquo;m planning to work my way though all the books I buy for decoration, I mean
never get around to reading. What&rsquo;s more is that I&rsquo;m going to review them here
too! That means that I&rsquo;ll both start reading <em>and</em> posting more! Win-win!</p>

<p>Apart from reviewing printed teachings (and the odd piece of fiction maybe)
I also have a couple of hardware projects coming up which I&rsquo;m going to share
with you guys. So hopefully there&rsquo;ll be a lot going on here on the blog in
the future!</p>

<p>Right now I have to go to sleep though, so I&rsquo;ll see you next time!</p>

<p>Happy Hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://erikbergenholtz.github.io/erikbergenholtz/blog/2015/04/14/helloWorld/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://erikbergenholtz.github.io/erikbergenholtz/blog/2015/04/14/helloWorld</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello, and welcome to my blog! My name is Erik Bergenholtz, and I am a
security enthusiast and hacker living in Sweden. I hope to expand my website in
the future, but for now this blog will have to do.</p>

<p>As I mentioned, I am a security enthusiast and hacker. I mostly enjoy
computer security, but physical security such as burglary alarms and lock
smithing is also quite amusing. This is what my blog will be about; security,
hacking, projects and perhaps the odd contemplation.</p>

<p>I am not sure what else to write in this first post, so I&rsquo;ll just leave it at
that. I&rsquo;m looking forward to sharing some of my projects, and I hope you&rsquo;ll
enjoy reading about them.</p>

<p>Until then, <strong>happy hacking</strong>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
