<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tags: Miscellaneous | Erik Bergenholtz' blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/categories/miscellaneous/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/"/>
  <updated>2018-02-03T23:25:01+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erik Bergenholtz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Year - Higher Resolution]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/12/31/new-year-higher-resolution/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-31T23:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/12/31/new-year-higher-resolution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s a new year, which means that it&rsquo;s time to make new year&rsquo;s resolutions that
you&rsquo;re not going to keep. Or maybe you will! I for one will really try to keep
mine, because I really want to make myself a better person. So what are my
new year&rsquo;s resolutions going to be?</p>

<p>First off, and I know that I&rsquo;ve said this a few times before, I am going to
read more. For reals this time. Thing is that I have a ton of books, both
fictional and factual, that I&rsquo;ve been eager to read. However, I have a severe
case of &ldquo;積ん読&rdquo; or <em>tsundoku</em>. It&rsquo;s a Japanese word for &ldquo;buying books
but not reading them&rdquo; (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tsundoku">seriously</a>).
Now I want to stop having this.. &ldquo;condition&rdquo;, I want to start reading. Not only
because books are expensive and I should not spend money unnecessarily, but
also because what I do when I don&rsquo;t read is quite stupid. Usually, I just
imgur or reddit, or play some game. Sure, gaming is good for relaxing, but so
is learning new things. So, my plan is to spend less time browsing reddit and
more time reading things. So, new year&rsquo;s resolution number one is that I shall
read one book a month.</p>

<p>The second one is something I am going to do together with my girlfriend. We&rsquo;re
going to not consume any unnecessary sugar for 100 days. This means no candy,
soda, alcohol, cookies or anything else like that for one hundred days, i.e.
until April 9th. We&rsquo;re not going to over do it, so sugar in food products is
OK.</p>

<p>Lastly there&rsquo;s the obligatory &ldquo;get in shape&rdquo; resolution. I have these fancy
(but ugly) Vibram Fivefinger shoes that&rsquo;s I&rsquo;ve been using too little. So I&rsquo;m
going to take up running again, at least once a week. Also I&rsquo;m going to try to
start lifting weights down at the gym. I&rsquo;m doing this not only to become a
Greek god (which I obviously will become), but also to relieve some stress.</p>

<p>So, that&rsquo;s my three new year&rsquo;s resolutions:</p>

<ul>
<li>Reading one book a month, be it fictional or educational</li>
<li>No excess sugar for 100 days</li>
<li>Start running at least once a week</li>
</ul>


<p>So that&rsquo;s it for this post. Sorry for deluding you into thinking I was getting
a 4k monitor or something that cool for the new year. Hopefully I will update
my rig during the year, and I&rsquo;ll keep you posted on that, but for now this is
all.</p>

<p>Happy hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
