<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tags: Gaming | Erik Bergenholtz' blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/categories/gaming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/"/>
  <updated>2017-08-13T17:50:38+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erik Bergenholtz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I've Had It With No Man's Sky]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/08/15/had-it-with-nms/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2016/08/15/had-it-with-nms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As probably nobody with even the slightest interest in gaming has missed, the
hype of the year has finally come out: No Man&rsquo;s Sky. The game where there is an
infinite, procedurally generated universe to discover and explore, creatures
created not by careful design but by artifical evolution to marvel at, alien
cultures to encounter and interact with! Over at
<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NoMansSkyTheGame">/r/NoMansSkyTheGame</a> people have
torn their hair in anticipation of this game. And I must admit, I was quite
excited about it as well. Becuase it sounds pretty cool, doesn&rsquo;t it? With all
that exploration to do, all those discoveries to be made.</p>

<p>Now I&rsquo;ve tried. I really have. I&rsquo;ve spent ten hours over the weekend trying to
get into it, but I just can&rsquo;t. The game is horrendous. I&rsquo;ve had it. It&rsquo;s not
just that there&rsquo;s nothing to do in the game, it&rsquo;s also that everything is
exactly the same and nothing makes sense! For instance I visited a quite
chilly planet, so to speak. The temperature was at -30 to -60 centrigrades.
Despite this there were liquid water! Fancy that, no ice! When I then fly over
to another planet in the same solar system I notice something interesting; the
exact same plants as I found on another planet <em>in another solar system</em> lives
there. Not something similar, the <em>exact</em> same but with a (presumably)
different name. Not to mention the creatures created by the artificial
evolution.
<a href="https://twitter.com/Britbongreturns/status/765190830894317568">This</a> post
by <a href="https://twitter.com/Britbongreturns">@Britbongreturns</a> sums it up quite
nicely, so I&rsquo;ll leave it at that.</p>

<p>Before I conclude this post, let&rsquo;s go over a few of the selling points on the
game&rsquo;s <a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/275850/#app_reviews_hash">Steam page</a>.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>&ldquo;<em>a galaxy to explore, filled with unique planets and lifeforms, and constant
 danger and action</em>&rdquo;</p>

<p>Well this is just a downright lie: The planets may be procedurally
generated, and therefore unique, but apparently reusing every resource
there is in the game isn&rsquo;t covered by this. Also, if there is so much
danger and action, how come I haven&rsquo;t experienced neither danger nor
action?</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;<em>Fly smoothly from deep space to planetary surfaces, with no loading
 screens, and no limits.</em>&rdquo;</p>

<p>That is actually true! There are no loading screens! Instead there is the
most terrible texture popping I have ever seen! Not only does it pop in
textures as you&rsquo;re closing up to them, but it &ldquo;unpops&rdquo; them as well; if you
have mined out a huge pillar of e.g. gold then you&rsquo;ll still see it at a
distance! Terrible!</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;<em>At the centre of the galaxy lies a irresistible pulse which draws you on a
 journey towards it</em>&rdquo;</p>

<p>Huh, the more you know. Apart from the exposition given right here I haven&rsquo;t
been given any incentive so far for going to the center of the galaxy.
Weird.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>To conclude this rant I&rsquo;d like to say that I didn&rsquo;t want a 60€ game with
horrible &ldquo;evolution&rdquo; in it. I already own a game like that: Spore! So now I&rsquo;m
done with this disappointment. I&rsquo;m going back to buying small, unknown indie
games via <a href="https://www.humblebundle.com/">HumbleBundle</a>, at least I usually
enjoy at least they&rsquo;re enjoyable for the most part.</p>

<p>/rant</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
