<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tags: Books | Erik Bergenholtz' blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/"/>
  <updated>2018-02-03T23:25:01+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Erik Bergenholtz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book Review: Hacking - the Art of Exploitation]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2018/02/03/book-review-hacking-the-art-of-exploitation/"/>
    <updated>2018-02-03T23:19:55+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2018/02/03/book-review-hacking-the-art-of-exploitation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This review was supposed to be published some months ago (in July last year,
to be specific), but wasn&rsquo;t because I put it in a folder where I&rsquo;d be sure to
find it again and then, of course, didn&rsquo;t. So if there&rsquo;s anything in there that
doesn&rsquo;t make sense in the context of having read the book now, rather than
during last year&rsquo;s vacation, it&rsquo;s because I did read it during last year&rsquo;s
vacation. Regardless, I stand by my opinion on the book, so here&rsquo;s the review.</em></p>

<p>Here it is. My review of <em><a href="https://www.nostarch.com/hacking2.htm">Hacking - The Art of Exploitation</a></em>
by Jon Erickson, published by <a href="https://www.nostarch.com">No Starch Press</a> (of
course). It&rsquo;s a book I first learned about many a year ago when I first got
interested for real in computer security, so somewhere around seven years ago.
Like <em>Gray Hat Hacking</em>, this is one of <em>the</em> books to read as an asipring
hacker according to the hacker community (at least it was back then). I bought
a copy of the book 2013, and it&rsquo;s been gathering dust on my bookshelf since. But
now, finally, I&rsquo;ve read it. So what are we waiting for, let&rsquo;s jump right in!</p>

<p>Unlike <em>Gray Hat Hacking</em>, which tries to be an introduction to many fields of
security, <em>The Art of Exploitation</em> tries to be an introduction to one aspect of
security, namely writing exploits. As a result, it goes further into depth in
this one subject than <em>Gray Hat Hacking</em> does in any subject, including
programming. A fundamental part of writing exploits is to understand how
computers work at a low level, and <em>The Art of Exploitation</em> aims to teach you
just that. Because of this, the first 100 pages of the book covers C programming
and some general x86 assymbly. I&rsquo;m aware that I gave <em>Gray Hat Hacking</em> a bit
of a bashing for covering programming, because I believe that you should know
programming before getting into hacking, but here it&rsquo;s much more in depth and
well explained. <em>Gray Hat Hacking</em> stopped at showing off if-statements and
for-loops, while <em>Art of Exploitation</em> goes all the way to dynamic memory,
function pointers, structs and file access. It also shows some of the basics of
GDB, end explains the stack, the heap and the different memory segments that are
used in a program. All in all, I believe that if you read the first chapter
carefully, do some exercises and write some programs yourself, you&rsquo;d be pretty
confident with C afterwards. Granted, you&rsquo;ll have to put down time to actually
learn how to write programs from a specification of course, but at least you
would know how to write the code once the structure of it is determined.</p>

<p>The rest of the book is more or less dedicated to exploiting. The second chapter
shows how a number of exploits like buffer overflows and fromat string exploits
work, and it does so by example. Accompanying the book is a LiveCD with an
Ubuntu installation containing all the tools and code used in the book. All
examples are walked through, step by step, and clearly show how to find the
vulnerability in the given program, how to construct the exploit and how to
execute it. The chapter following this takes this to the next level by adding
networking to the mix. It starts off by talking about networks in general,
explaining the OSI model layer by layer, and then moves on to some network
programming using both the <code>socket()</code> interface in C, as well as more abstract
libraries like <code>libnet</code> and <code>libpcap</code>. It finally explains how to write tools
for things like DoS attacks, ARP spoofing and TCP/IP hijacking. Once networking
is covered, the book moves on to showing how to write your own shellcode, as up
to this point all the shellcode has been predesigned to do the right thing. It
goes through how to use syscalls to do what you want, how to open up shells,
bind shells to network connections, and how to optimize the shellcode. Next,
countermeasures are covered as well as ways around these countermeasures.
Finally, a brief and high level introduction to cryprology is given, which shows
off how to break RC4 (the cryptographic function used by WEP) among other
things.</p>

<p>Needless to say, the book does cover a lot of things, but it&rsquo;s still quite
focused. Most of the exploits that are shown are based on the idea of injecting
code into a running program, and redirecting the execution of the program to the
injected code. Because of this, and the fact that all the exploits are written
by the reader and not just executed by a prebuilt tool, the book doesn&rsquo;t feel
too spread out and also manages to convey understanding on the subjects, rather
than being a glorified manpage. Apart from this, the text is also quite
approachable, which makes it easy to take in the information. The examples are
worked through step by step, showing all the steps along the way, and the steps
are clearly explained. Many of the programs being exploited are quite trivial
and have blindingly obvious flaws, but the point of the book is not to become a
1337 h4xXx0R^ that can <a href="https://youtu.be/Bmz67ErIRa4">hack the Gibson</a>, but to
get the reader into the mindset of a hacker and to know what kinds of flaws to
look for when trying to find exploits in real life software. This is something
it does a great job with.</p>

<p>One thing you might&rsquo;ve noticed is that I mentioned that all the code is readily
available on the supplied LiveCD, but I didn&rsquo;t complain about it like I did with
<em>Black Hat Python</em>. This might seem hypocritical, but I have my reasons for
thinking it&rsquo;s okay with this book. Firtly, most of the things that the book
actually tries to teach you are concepts that can&rsquo;t really be put into code.
Sure, you can just read the book, see all the examples in GDB that are shown in
the book, and then pat yourself on the back for becoming a hacker. But if you
want to actually try running any of the exploits to see them in action, you&rsquo;ll
have to do some work yourself as memory addresses changes. Moreover, most of
the supplied code is either shellcode that you need prebuilt until the fourth
chapter of book, or programs that you&rsquo;ll try to exploit. Writing these yourself
if of course very good exercise, but for someone like me who knows programming
quite well and just want to learn how to write exploit, having to write the
500 line web server myself would just be a distraction. Having the code
available, ready to be compiled, lets you focus on what the book actually is
about. Another redeeming factor is that the book actually explains what&rsquo;s being
attempted <em>before</em> showing the code in the book, so you can give it a go first.
Because of these things, I appreciate the code being available.</p>

<p>So, to wrap this up, did I learn something, and who would I recommend this to?
The answer to the first question is undoubtably &ldquo;yes&rdquo;, I learned quite a bit.
I knew of most attacks since before, but reading this gave me a better
understanding of why they work, and how. I also learned that I need to get
better at assembler, because optimizing shellcode for both size and to remove
NULL-bytes can be a bit tricky. In other words, expect a review on an ASM book
some time in the future. The answer to the second question is a bit more tricky.
On the one hand I think this is a book that, in part at least, would benefit
everyone who does software development at some level. On the other hand it might
be a bit too in-depth if your only goal is to understand how the exploits work
on a high level to know what to avoid doing. Because of this, I think I&rsquo;m going
to settle for the answer that anyone who is interested in security should read
this book, everyone else might want to skim some of it but maybe not read the
whole thing cover to cover. Also, I do think that because of the thorough
introduction to programming in the beginning, as long as you&rsquo;re taking the time
to work through everything and not just use the prebuilt code, people of any
level should be able to follow reasonably well. I do still think you should have
a firm grasp of how computers work <em>before</em> you delve into security though.</p>

<p>That being said, I am now off to do.. other things. I&rsquo;m thinking of picking up
<em>Web application Hacker&rsquo;s Handbook</em> and work through that, or try to find a nice
VM with juicy vulnerabilities to practice on. Regardless, I&rsquo;ll see you later!</p>

<p>Happy Hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book Review: Exploding the Phone by Phil Lapsley]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2017/07/30/book-review-exploding-the-phone-by-phil-lapsley/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-30T12:47:44+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2017/07/30/book-review-exploding-the-phone-by-phil-lapsley</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right <a" src="href="http://www.groveatlantic.com/bigcovers/9780802120618.jpg">http://www.groveatlantic.com/bigcovers/9780802120618.jpg</a>" width="150" height="250" title="Cover" >
There we are. I have finally managed to make it through Phil Lapsely&rsquo;s book
<a href="http://explodingthephone.com/"><em>Exploding the Phone</em></a>. Despite taking me 2.5
years to get through (because I&rsquo;ve put it away for months at a time several
times, and started over reading it an equal amount of times) I did enjoy
reading it. The book, which is some 330 pages long, covers the adventures of
the <em>phone phreaks</em>, i.e. the individuals who used their wits out outsmart the
telephone system back in the day (50-70s). They were the telephone system&rsquo;s
equivalent to today&rsquo;s computer hackers, and to a large extent they set the
stage for the computer hackers themselves.</p>

<p>The book starts off way back in the late 1800s when when the Bell Telephone
Company was created, to it&rsquo;s demise in 1983. Most of the events in the book
happened in the 50-70s, however. The book lets us follow the advent and
evolution of phreaking, and get to know big names in the game such as Bill
Acker, Joe Engerssia and John Draper. Their adventures were quite awesome, in
the old sense of the word. If you want to know about what the things they
actually did you&rsquo;ll have to pick up the book; I am not going to spoil it here.</p>

<p>I would assume that most people who pick this book up are somewhat like me:
interested in technical things and probably security to some extent too. In
such case, I&rsquo;m sure they&rsquo;d be interested in how things actually worked. What
were the vulnerabilities that enabled the phreaking, and why did they work?
These are things made me want the book, and after reading it I am by no means
disappointed. The book is filled with enough technical detail that it&rsquo;s easy
to understand how and why the attacks worked, but it&rsquo;s not enough to push the
story about the phreaks out of the way. All in all, I think that it gives the
right amount of coverage.</p>

<p>Despite having a lot of technical information, the book is quite easy to read.
The language isn&rsquo;t too advanced, and everything is clearly explained. It is,
however, a bit messy chronologically. Because it follows a lot of stories
revolving around a lot of people, it isn&rsquo;t written in an entirely chronological
order. On the grand scale of things it is, but it&rsquo;s not uncommon that the
author goes on a lengthy tangent in the middle of a story. It&rsquo;s not done
needlessly or poorly, as the transitions feel natural and the tangents provide
information that&rsquo;s necessary to understand what is going on. However, it does
mess up the time line a bit, so keeping track of who lives where and who did
what in which order is a bit tricky. It doesn&rsquo;t take away much from the
experience though.</p>

<p>So what&rsquo;s the verdict? It&rsquo;s clearly positive, I would highly recommend reading
the book. It&rsquo;s interesting and gives a lot of insight into the history of
today&rsquo;s hacker culture. Despite it taking me 2.5 years to get through the book,
I don&rsquo;t think it took too many hours to read once I actually sat down with it.
For me, it was a very worthwhile read and I&rsquo;d happily read more books like
it.</p>

<p>That concludes my review, and with that I&rsquo;m up to 6 books read this year. That
means that I&rsquo;m just one month behind where I should be, according to my new
year&rsquo;s resolution of reading one book a month. I best get to it then, so until
next time</p>

<p>Happy Hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book Review - Ansible: From Beginner to Pro]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2017/07/20/book-review-ansible-from-beginner-to-pro/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-20T01:41:33+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2017/07/20/book-review-ansible-from-beginner-to-pro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s time for another book review. This time of Michael Heap&rsquo;s
<a href="http://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484216606">Ansible: From Beginner to Pro</a>,
published by <a href="http://www.apress.com/">Apress</a>. The 200 page book is, as the
name suggests, about the orchestration tool Ansible. It&rsquo;s a tool that I don&rsquo;t
have any previous experience of, but I&rsquo;m looking forward to trying it out in
the real world! Now, let&rsquo;s jump into it!</p>

<p>For being such a short book it covers quite a few topics. It assumes no
previous knowledge, and starts from the very beginning. It then walks through
the various components of Ansible projects, like inventory files (files
containing lists of hosts to run Ansible against), roles and how to write your
own modules with Python. The explanations are clear, and throughout the book a
running example (consisting of a WordPress installation) is used to demonstrate
the different topics. The nice tone and spacious layout also contributes to make
reading the book a pleasant experience, and I managed to read the full thing
cover to cover in about a weekend without trying too hard.</p>

<p>So, are there anything that&rsquo;s not that great about the book? Well, I had issues
with a few steps along the way, and while I did manage to solve I would&rsquo;ve
liked some form of guidance from the book. It doesn&rsquo;t cover troubleshooting at
all, which come to think of it none of the other books I&rsquo;ve reviewed have
either (I particularly remember trying desperately to understand the Haskell
error messages I got when reading <em>Learn you a Haskell</em>, which are all quite
cryptic). It was a while since I read the book, so I don&rsquo;t remember specifically
what the issues where, but I do remember that for a beginner like myself the
solution wasn&rsquo;t immediately obvious. Apart from this I have no big issues with
the book. I enjoyed both it and the tool quite a bit, and I hope the other
books from Apress have the same standard (I have a few in my backlog).</p>

<p>Now, on to the big question: Am I an Ansible pro now? After all, that&rsquo;s
what the book&rsquo;s name suggests I should be. To be fair, I think that <em>pro</em>
might be a slight exaggeration. While I think that I could probably orchestrate
a server reasonably well using Ansible at this point, there&rsquo;s still a lot to
learn. The book mentions some best practices for various parts of the tool, but
my experience from other areas tell me that while I may understand these, it&rsquo;ll
take a bit of active use of the tool before they&rsquo;re fully internalized. That
being said, I do believe that I know enough to orchestrate a server. And I will
    soon know for sure; I bought a VPS recently and I plan to orchestrate it using
Ansible, both for simplicity and for practice. This will happen sometime during
the coming week, so I&rsquo;ll get back to you then. I also have some neat ideas
regarding orchestrating localhost that I want to try out, so and I&rsquo;ll let you
read all about it once I&rsquo;ve given it a go.</p>

<p>To conclude, would I recommend this book? If you&rsquo;re a sysadmin on any level,
be it on a hobby level like me or a professional level like not me, yes. It&rsquo;s
a tool that makes the setting up of a server a lot easier, and the fact that
you can dry-run your playbooks in a virtual environment without any fuzz is
great. If you&rsquo;re not a sysadmin I wouldn&rsquo;t recommend it though. It&rsquo;s a pleasant
read nonetheless, but I don&rsquo;t think you&rsquo;ll get much out of it. Unless, of
course, my little experiment works. Then you might want to have a look at it
for ricing reasons. We&rsquo;ll see I guess. Until then!</p>

<p>Happy Hacking</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Thoughts on Gray Hat Hacking: The Ethical Hacker's Handbook]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2017/07/11/my-thoughts-on-gray-hat-hacking/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2017/07/11/my-thoughts-on-gray-hat-hacking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here we are again, I&rsquo;ve actually read another book. That makes four this year,
out of which three have been on some form of computer related topic. So my
New Year&rsquo;s resolution to read twelve books this year is actually looking like
it&rsquo;s doable.</p>

<p>But enough beating around be bush, if you&rsquo;re reading this it&rsquo;s because you want
to know what I think of <a href="http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~ace/media/gray-hat-hacking.pdf">Gray Hat Hacking: The Ethical Hacker&rsquo;s Handbook</a>,
so here&rsquo;s what I think of it: I&rsquo;m not sure. I think that I may be a poor judge,
because I was expecting more than I got. See, this book is quite praised in
hacker circles, at least as I remember it from the days when I used to hang out
in hacker forums. It is one of <em>the</em> books you should read if you want to get
into the world of hacking. So knowing this I obviously expected miracles, more
or less, when I started reading. Unfortunately, that is not what <em>I</em> got.</p>

<p>Before we go any further, I want to point out a few things. Firstly, I have not
read this cover to cover. I&rsquo;ve read the better part of it, but I&rsquo;ve skipped
quite some text that I didn&rsquo;t have a need for right now. This mostly involves
fluff like how to use specific tools, what it means to be an <em>Ethical Hacker</em>.
Secondly, since I have an education in computer security where I have actually
had this book as course literature (I didn&rsquo;t read it at the time though), I knew
a lot of these things before. This is part of the reason why I didn&rsquo;t get the
miracle I was expecting. With that out of the way, let&rsquo;s get into the meat of'er!</p>

<p>The book quite hefty at 672 pages. It covers <em>a lot</em> of topics, ranging from how
to report found vulnerabilities to basic programming (I&rsquo;m coming back to this
later) to quite advanced tricks to get around protection schemes. This is why I
believe that it&rsquo;s considered such a good book to read if you want to enter the
world of hacking; it does give an introduction to a great many things. However,
some of these fields are covered so briefly that they might as well have left
them out. This includes SQL and XSS injections, that are only really touched
upon. Other topics, buffer overflows in particular, are elaborated on. The
explanations of these topics are well composed, with working(ish) examples,
complete with code, explanations and references. This allow you to follow along
for the most part, which is great! As opposed to Black Hat Python, where the
code examples comes first and the explanation afterwards, here the explanation
of the vulnerability comes first and the exploit is then iteratively
constructed, showing all steps along the way. The only real problem I have with
this is that their type setting for the code segment is quite bad, and sometimes
separate lines are printed on the same line. This is really a minor complaint
though.</p>

<p>One thing that is not the books fault, but decreases the value of it none the
less, is that it is a book and it&rsquo;s written in 2011. This means that some of the
things brought up in it is no longer possible, or no longer relevant. For
instance, the book walked throught the process of injecting shellcode via the
<code>.dtors</code> section of a program (I&rsquo;m not explaining that further, not in this
post at least). That section is replaces with <code>.fini_array</code> since GCC 4.7, which
works differently and makes the covered attack impossible. There&rsquo;s likely a
similar attack that exploits the new format, but for obvious reasons the book
doesn&rsquo;t cover it. There are a number of such instances, but as mentioned it&rsquo;s
not the fault of the authors but rather the ever-changing nature of the field.</p>

<p>Another thing that I find strange about the book is it&rsquo;s pacing. It&rsquo;s covering
fairly advanced attacks and how to construct your own shellcode, while at the
same time covering basic programming. This section is really quite short and as
I&rsquo;m quite adept at programming I only skimmed it, but I could see that it was on
the level of &ldquo;every C program needs a function called <code>main()</code>&rdquo;. In other words,
that part of the text was aimed at someone who has never seen a line of code.
This is odd to me, as security is no basic topic. Sure, there are a ton of
script kiddies who run around on the interwebs thinking they&rsquo;re 1337 hax0rz
because the figured out how to download LOIC (or whatever is the latest and
greatest DDoS tool now-a-days), but this is a book that aims to educate security
professionals. Demanding a certain amount of previous knowledge of how C,
memory and such works would not be too much to ask in my opinion. Especially
when, as I said, shellcode construction is covered. This involves writing
(short) C programs that do what you want, compiling them and removing any
unnecessary ASM that the compiler added, only to then assemble and extract the
opcodes. In other words, it&rsquo;s nothing you&rsquo;d be able to do confidently if you
don&rsquo;t know C before you start reading.</p>

<p>Apart from this I like the book. I didn&rsquo;t get much out of it, but that is
because I already knew most of it. The parts I didn&rsquo;t know where quite
interesting to read about, and as I said it covers the topics well. Because of
this I&rsquo;d agree with the statement that this is one of <em>the books</em> to read if you
want to get going with <em>ethical</em> hacking. Do yourself a favour and wait until
you&rsquo;re at least somewhat proficient in C and x86 assembler before you pick up
the book though, as you might have a hard time understanding some of the
examples otherwise.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for now, I hope you enjoyed this.. reviewish. Until next time,</p>

<p>Happy Hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Initial Impressions: Black Hat Python]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2017/07/10/initial-impressions-bhp/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.erikbergenholtz.se/blog/2017/07/10/initial-impressions-bhp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The other day I dug my teeth into a new piece of literature:
<a href="https://www.nostarch.com/blackhatpython">Black Hat Python: Python Programming for Hackers and Pentesters</a>
by <a href="https://www.nostarch.com/">No Starch Press</a>. Anyone who&rsquo;s spent more then
five minutes on this site probably knows that No Starch is my favorite publisher
and that I think they usually publish books of high quality. Spoiler alert; this
book does not fall in that category.</p>

<p>Before I go on, I want to give a short disclaimer though. This is by no means a
<em>book review</em>. I have not read the whole thing cover to cover (yet), I have just
read the first few chapters and put it away because I really disliked the way
the author&rsquo;s style of teaching. I plan on reading the full thing at some point
and give a <em>proper</em> review, but I want to give some kind of a heads up for
anyone reading. So, let&rsquo;s do it!</p>

<p>First off, I was quite excited to read this. I enjoy working with Python, and
would say that it&rsquo;s probably the language I use the most. I&rsquo;m also quite
interested in computer security, and one of my previous goals was to become a
professional pentester. So obviously this book was quite appealing. The book is
written by Justin Seitz, who at the time of writing writing the book worked at
Immunity Inc with security analysis. He&rsquo;s also written another book for No
Starch Press called <a href="https://www.nostarch.com/ghpython.htm">Gray Hat Python</a>
(which I&rsquo;ll get arount to reading Soon™), so it all seems good! The book covers
a range of topics, from how to set up the testing environment to how to automate
forenic tasks, spread trojans via github, and playing around with the network.
From just looking at it from the outside, it looks like a really nice book (it
has a nice cover too!)</p>

<p>Unfortunately, as the saying goes, you should not judge a book by it&rsquo;s cover.
While the text itself holds up to the quality of the other No Starch books I&rsquo;ve
read, the actual <em>content</em> of the book does not. Each section in the book
describes a problem, like needing a quick way to send commands to a compromised
server. The text then guides you through a solution to the problem, and this is
where the problems start. Firstly, the solution is presented <em>before</em> the
explanation of even the steps to take. This might seem like a small issue, and
maybe it is for some, but I prefer to give it a go myself first, <em>before</em> I look
at a solution. I know this might be hard with books like this, but just listing
what the solution must do isn&rsquo;t too much to ask, is it? The second thing that
bugged me, which is what made me put the book away, is the actual explanations
themselves. They are really short, and don&rsquo;t explain much at all. To showcase
this, let&rsquo;s have a look at the following example:</p>

<pre><code class="python">class Server (paramiko.ServerInterface):
    def _init_(self):
        self.event = threading.Event()
    def check_channel_request(self, kind, chanid):
        if kind == 'session':
            return paramiko.OPEN_SUCCEEDED
        return paramiko.OPEN_FAILED_ADMINISTRATIVELY_PROHIBITED
    def check_auth_password(self, username, password):
        if (username == 'justin') and (password == 'lovesthepython'):
            return paramiko.AUTH_SUCCESSFUL
        return paramiko.AUTH_FAILED
</code></pre>

<p>A simple enough python class, that is used to build an SSH-server to send
commands through to the client, which is uploaded to the victim. The
explanation for the code is as follows:</p>

<blockquote><p>just like we did earlier in the chapter, and then SSHinize it</p></blockquote>

<p>This is not the first thing the book covered on SSH using the Paramiko library,
but a class was never used. Also, none of the Paramiko flags were used earlier.
But their names are good, so it&rsquo;s easy enough to understand the function of the
Server-class anyway. Now, let&rsquo;s skip forward in the code:</p>

<pre><code class="python">bhSession = paramiko.Transport(client)
bhSession.add_server_key(host_key)
server = Server()
try:
    bhSession.start_server(server=server)
except paramiko.SSHException, x:
    print '[-] SSH negotiation failed.'
chan = bhSession.accept(20)
</code></pre>

<p>None of this has been used before, but it&rsquo;s all pretty obvious; set <code>client</code> (
which is an already connected socket) as the socket on which to transport the
SSH session, add a keyfile, build a server-object and use that as the server.
The explanation for this is</p>

<blockquote><p>configure the authentication methods</p></blockquote>

<p>I&rsquo;m sorry, what? I guess this is technically correct, but it doesn&rsquo;t explain
<em>anything</em>. Sure, it&rsquo;s not that hard to understand, but still. The thing that
really annoys me is this: <code>bhSession.start_server(server=server)</code>. <code>bhSession</code>
is a paramiko-object of some kind, and to that objects member function
<code>start_server()</code> we pass our homebrewed Server-class. This means that, since
it will be used by a function in a library, the Server-class have to have some
functions and variables that should respond to different things. These are quite
important pieces of information if you want to build something yourself rather
than just copy and paste from a book. Alas, if I want to learn that I have to
consult the Paramiko documentation, because there isn&rsquo;t an explanation within
sight in the book.</p>

<p>I really don&rsquo;t mind reading documentation, but I do mind paying $34 for a book
that supposedly should teach me something, only to be forced to read open
documentation if I want more understanding than copying, pasting and running can
give. Fortunately I got the book in a HumbleBundle, so I hardly payed for it.
And maybe it gets better later in the book, but right now I don&rsquo;t have time to
find out. As I said, this is very much a first imporession of the book and I
will get back to it. I just really think it&rsquo;s a shame that they didn&rsquo;t make it
twice as long (it&rsquo;s just short of 165 pages) and elaborated on the explanations
more, so that you don&rsquo;t need to consult the documentation to understand what&rsquo;s
going on.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for my rant on this book. I&rsquo;ll revisit it Sometime™ and write a real
review. But for now this will have to do. I&rsquo;ll have a review on another book I
recently read shortly, but until then</p>

<p>Happy Hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
